Отані.
Otani-kun~
Ра-но-чку.
Good morning~
Гидота!
Gross!
Чого це гидота?!
What do you mean, "gross"?!
Як ти поводиш себе зі своєю дівчиною?
Is that the kind of attitude you should have towards your girlfriend?
А ти якась не в надміру зверхня?
Don't you think your attitude is a little arrogant?
Я натерпілася до сьогодні.
I've suffered a lot up until now.
Тепер відіграюсь.
I need compensation.
Відіграєшся?
What do you mean, "compensation"?
Ачику!
A-chan!
Раночку.
Good morning.
А, та дівчина,
Ah, this girl is...
сусідка Отані.
...Otani's neighbor.
Меймей!
Meimei-chan!
Мімі!
It's Mimi!
Твоя дівчина дотепна.
Your girlfriend sure is funny.
О ні, спізнюємося!
Oh no! We're gonna be late!
Бо ти забарився.
That's because you took so long.
Бо це ти тупила.
That's because you were being stupid.
Побачимось, Мімі.
See ya, Mimi-chan.
Оголошення!! Небезпечна красуня ревнує!!
Declaration of War!! The Dangerous Beauty Who Burns With Jealousy!!
Чому?! Чому не сказала?!
What's this?! Why didn't you tell us?!
Коли ви?
When did this happen?
Вітаю вас.
Як це було?
I see. Congratulations.
What did you say when you asked her out?
Чудово. Вітаю.
Oh? That's great. Congratulations.
Це правда?
Is it true, Senpai?
Аблалавлалал!
Ahdsakafajdags!
Це чудово.
This is wonderful.
Я схвильована!
I'm so moved!
Нарешті комедійний дует став парою.
So the comedy duo is finally a couple.
Вітаю!
Congratulations!
Дякую.
Thank you.
Та що ви ото.
Don't make such a big deal out of it.
Чому?!
Why?!
Скажи мені, Рісо!
Please tell me why, Risa!
Задумайся! Це дивно! Такий хлопець...
Think about this seriously! It's weird! Choosing a guy like that...
Що ти сказав?
What do you mean, "a guy like that"?
Заціпся, карлику!
Beat it, mini-man!
Знахабнів.
Don't get cocky.
Це хто знахабнів?!
Who's getting cocky?!
Ти...
You...
Ти..
Добре...
Fine...
Я знав, що цей день колись настане.
I knew this day would come eventually.
Згадала.
Oh... that's right.
Вчитель шукав вас двох.
Sensei was looking for you two earlier.
Уже?
It's over already?
Ви забули принести роботи?
Did you forget to do your summer homework?
Так.
Yes.
Вибачте.
Sorry.
Що ще тут скажеш.
Well, at this stage there's nothing more that can be said.
Здайте до понеділка.
Just turn it in by Monday.
Так.
Yes.
Я взагалі за це забула.
I totally forgot about it.
Давай зробимо її разом.
Let's work on it together.
Де?
Where?
У бібліотеці з іншими?
Do you want to go to the library with Suzuki and the others?
Не піде.
Bad idea.
У тихому місці як бібліотека мене дрижаки б'ють.
If I'm in a quiet place like the library, I'll be all "eek".
І мене б'ють теж.
It will be all "eek", won't it?
Може у мене?
Want to come to my place?
Вітаю, Ачику.
Welcome home, A-chan.
Ти і дівчину привів?
So you brought your girlfriend over?
Що ти тут робиш?
What are you doing here?
Я принесла молоко.
I brought today's milk for you.
Молоко?
M-Milk?
Вона тягає молоко, бо думає що я так виросту.
She brings me milk everyday, saying it'll make me taller.
Сьогодні я купила дещо круте.
Today I've brought something really great.
Висококальцієве молоко з пасовищ Хоккайдо
This is high calcium milk, straight from the pastures of Hokkaido.
Що смішного?!
What's so funny?!
Що ж, молоко...
Well, milk...
А тепер іди додому.
If there's nothing else, hurry up and go home.
Але я хочу поспілкуватись з твоєю дівчиною.
Awww. But I wanted to chat with your girlfriend.
Ні. Ми будемо зараз вчитися.
No. We're gonna study now, so you can't.
Нічого, Отані.  Це недовго.
It's okay, Otani. It'll just be for a bit.
Так!
Yeah!
Але недовго.
Just for a bit, okay?
Добре.
Understood.
Ачику, можна тебе?
A-chan, could you come here for a sec?
Та що там таке.
What is it? Geez...
Як мило...
How cute...
Мімі, ти така висока.
Mimi-chan, you're pretty tall and slim.
Який у тебе зріст?
How tall are you?
172 см.
172cm.
Ого! Як і я!
Wow! Same as me!
Справді?
Really?
Але Ачик казав, що не хоче дівчину вищу за нього.
But A-chan always said he'd never go out with a girl taller than him.
А. Точно.
Ah. That'd be right.
Він чомусь не зважає на мій зріст.
But he doesn't seem to mind my height for some reason.
А знаєш, що колишня Ачика була низенькою?
Hey, did you know that A-chan's last girlfriend was really short?
Так, я знаю.
Yeah, I know.
Маленька та мила.
She was small and cute.
Ось чому я від нього відмовилась.
That's why I gave up on A-chan.
Мімі, тобі подобається Отані?
You like Otani, Mimi-chan?
Але Ачик любить низеньких.
But A-chan only likes short girls...
А я висока.
...and I'm tall.
Тому я щодня приношу йому молоко, щоб він підріс.
That's why I bring him milk everyday, so that he'll grow taller.
Он як...
I-I see...
Я вирішила, що стану його дівчиною, коли він підросте.
I decided that when A-chan grew taller than me, I'd become his girlfriend.
Ти, цей. Вибач, мабуть...
Um... uh... Sorry, I guess...
Чорт. Я облажалась.
Damn. I missed.
"Вибач"?
"Sorry"?
Ти бісиш мене!
You've got some nerve!
Яким лихом ти його причарувала?
What kind of dirty trick did you pull to get him, eh?
Хочеш я запхаю тобі в носа локшину і зав'яжу вузла?
Do you want me to thread a noodle through your nostrils and tie a chignon?
Ні. Не хочу.
Noo. No, I don't...
Ачик не може мати іграшкову дівчину.
A-chan can't possibly have a girlfriend like toy.
М-м-м-імі
M-M-Mimi-chan...
Не промовляй моє ім'я цим гидким голосом.
Don't say my name in that disgusting voice!
Підійдеш до Ачика,
If you get any closer to A-chan,
я перетворю твоє життя на пекло.
I'll make what's left of your life extremely painful.
А ось чай.
I brought tea.
Отані! Врятуй!
Otani! Save me!
Кексик! Кексик!
Cake! Cake!
Я хочу його!
I want the Mont Blanc cake!
Можна?
Can I start?
Прошу.
G-Go ahead.
Твоя дівчина чудова!
Your girlfriend is really nice!
То мені примарилося?
Was that a hallucination just now?
Що таке, Коїзумі?
What's the matter, Koizumi?
Нічого.
Uh... Nothing.
Не примарилося.
It wasn't a hallucination.
Що з тобою?
What's up with you?
Мімі, доїси і додому.
Mimi, after you finish that, go home, okay?
Добре.
Okay.
Я й не знала, що вона модель.
I had no idea she was a model.
Це сусідка Отані?
So that's Otani's neighbor?
Яка красуня.
She looks amazing.
О, це Мімі.
Oh, it's Mimi.
Казати щось Отані немає сенсу.
Saying anything to Otani would be pointless.
Що ж, немає приводу хвилюватись.
Well, there's no point in worrying.
Хочеш піти розважитись?
Want to go have some fun, now that we've turned in our homework?
Ходім! Ходім!
Let's! Let's!
Що б не трапилось,
No matter what happens to me or what's said to me,
я буду щаслива, поки я з Отані.
I'll be happy as long as I have Otani's love.
Ачику!
A-chan!
Що ти тут робиш?
What are you doing here?
Ми з твоєю дівчиною так поладнали.
Your girlfriend and I are really getting along,
Погуляємо разом. Так?
We're going to hang out together today, Right?
Добре. Йдете тоді попереду.
Right, right. In that case, you two go on ahead.
А ти, Ачику?
What about you, A-chan?
Не хочу, щоб мене стиснуло між двома амазонками.
I don't want to walk home stuck between two amazons.
Будеш наче полонений прибулець.
You'll look like a captured alien.
Приб'ю тебе!
I'll smack you!
Торба...
Man...
Зажди! Отані!
Ah! Wa-Wait! Otani!
Агов.
Hey.
Зрозуміла, дівко?
Get it yet, hag?
Треба поговорити.
We need to have a little talk.
Та чому все так?
Why has it come to this?
Пропалить зараз.
She's totally staring me down.
Як тобі вдалося почати зустрічатись з Ачиком?
How did someone like you manage to get to the point of going out with A-chan?
Я старалася!
I-I worked really hard!
Дурепа! Я теж старалася!
You idiot! I've been working really hard too!
Ми з ним разом мила пара, еге ж?
I'm really cute when I'm with A-chan, aren't I?
Я поводжу себе так з нашої зустрічі.
I've been acting like that ever since I met him.
Уявляєш як тяжко?
Do you have any idea how tiring that is?
Мабуть важко...
Th-That would be difficult...
І це не все.
And that's not all.
Я давала Ачику молоко щодня,
I give A-chan milk every single day,
але він не виріс зовсім.
But he hasn't grown at all since his first year of middle school.
Правда?
Seriously?
Правда.
Seriously.
А я була вже 170 см, коли навчалась у початковій школі.
I, on the other hand, was already over 170cm when I was in elementary school.
Я була 168 см у 6 класі.
I was already 168cm when I was in sixth grade.
Та ну. Серйозно?
No way. Are you serious?
Мене завжди ставили позаду ще з дитсадка.
Man, I've been put back because of my height since I was in kindergarten.
І мене! І мене!
Me too! Me too!
Я була вище за найвищого хлопця.
I was even taller than the tallest boy.
Я теж!
Me too!
Ще та халепа, скажи?
It's a real pain, huh?
Що б не робила - завжди у центрі уваги.
No matter what you do, you always draw attention.
Точно.
Totally.
Вчитель помічає як балакаєш
If you talk, even just for a second, the teacher always sees-
Стоп! Чого це я спілкуюсь з такою дурепою?
Hey! Why the hell am I reminiscing with an idiot like you?!
Намагалася застати зненацька?
Uh... You were trying to catch me off guard?
Заціпся!
Shut up!
Коли Ачик почав зустрічатися з тією милою низенькою дівчиною, я повністю здалася.
When A-chan was going out with that short, cute girl, I completely gave up.
Зрозуміло. Ти думала, що немає шансів.
Naturally. You'd think you had no chance with your height.
Я розумію.
I understand.
Скажи?
Right?
Та дівчина мила.
That girl was really sweet.
Я думала, що всередині вона жахлива.
I thought that deep down she would've been nasty.
Так. Не те що ти, Мімі.
Yeah. She's not like you, Mimi-chan.
Так, так. Усередині я жахлива.
Yeah, yeah. Deep down I'm really a nasty-
Закрий рота!
Shut that damn mouth of yours!
Кого ти назвала  "жахливою"?!
Who the hell are you calling "nasty", you idiot?!
Вибач.
S-Sorry.
І після шикарної дівчини він обрав тебе?
So after he broke up with that great girlfriend, he moved on to this?
Високу й дурну!
Tall and stupid!
Я не програю тобі.
In any case, I'm not going to lose to you.
Я заберу собі Ачика.
I'm definitely going to win A-chan back.
На цьому усе.
That's all I have to say.
Зажди!
W-Wait!
Чого?
What is it?
So...Sorry. Could you lend me some money?
У мене всього 50 ієн.
I only have 50 yen on me.
50...
Ти здуріла ходити в ресторани з пустим гаманцем!
You've got some guts, walking into a family restaurant with only that much cash on you!
Я забула, що купила цей журнал.
I forgot that I bought a magazine today.
Ти така мила і гарна, що я аж забула.
You looked so cute and sweet that I totally forgot.
Ой, нічого не подієш.
Well, I guess that can't be helped.
Я позичу тобі грошей.
It was a special situation today, so I'll lend you some money.
Яка ти мила.
Wow. You sure are nice.
Гаманець забула. І що тепер робити?!
I think I left my purse at work. What should we do?!
Що робитимемо?!
What should we do?!
Не знаю...
No idea...
З вас 630 ієн.
The total comes to 630 yen.
Про що ви думали?
What were you thinking?
Пробач.
I'm really sorry.
Ачику..
A-chan.
Що тобі полюбилося в ній?
Just what is it that you like about her?
Чого ти?!
What's this, all of a sudden?!
Вона не схожа на твою колишню.
Well, she's nothing like your last girlfriend.
Вона вища за тебе,
She's taller than you,
і робить дурниці.
and she goes to family restaurants with only 50 yen on her.
Не бачу, що в ній гарного.
I just can't see what's so great about her.
Зараз не місце й не час.
This isn't the time or place to talk about this.
Скажи! Я маю знати!
Tell me! I need to know!
Не маєш. Це не твоє діло.
You don't need to. It's not like it's any of your business.
Отані...
Otani...
Це моє діло!
It is my business!
Ти мені подобаєшся більше ніж їй.
I like you much more than she does!
Мімі...
Mimi-chan...
Ти серйозно?
Are you serious?
Ачику, ти дурень!
You're an idiot, A-chan!
Мімі?
Mimi?
Я за нею.
I'll go after her.
Га? Сті...
Huh? Wai-
Я розумію, що відчуває Мімі.
After all, I understand how Mimi-chan feels.
Ачик сказав щось?
Did A-chan say anything?
Він злий на мене?
Is he angry at me?
Ні, він не злий.
No. he's not angry.
Але я накричала на нього й назвала дурнем.
But I... I yelled at him and called him an idiot.
Ачику, ти дурень!
You're an idiot, A-chan!
Не переживай за це.
You don't need to worry about that.
Він же справді дурень.
He really is an idiot, after all.
Як він міг так відповісти на зізнання? От дурень.
How could he say that in response to a confession? That idiot...
Ачик не дурень!
A-chan is not an idiot!
Кожен би так відреагував!
Anyone would be shocked by a sudden confession like that!
Це я неправа.
I'm the one who was in the wrong.
Не кажи про нього так!
Don't say bad things about A-chan!
Я ніколи так його не називала.
I've never talked to him that way before.
Я не втрималась і бовкнула не думаючи.
I lost it and said something I shouldn't have...
Це все через тебе, корово!
This is all your fault, you cow!
Це через тебе моє життя котиться під укіс!
It's your fault that my life is falling apart!
Що робитимеш, га?!
What are you gonna do about it, eh?!
Язика миші з'їли? Чого мовчиш?
Cat got your tongue? Why don't you try responding?
Хочеш бійки, курво?
Are you lookin' for a fight, you dumb bitch?!
Мі...мі?
Mi...mi?
Йойки...
Oh dear...
Вона тепер мабуть засмучена, що ти побачив її справжню.
She must be really down now that you've seen her true colors.
Ти про що?
What do you mean by that?
Хочеш сказати, що Мімі
Are you trying to tell me that the Mimi I know...
не така?
...is fake?
Звісно вона поводиться мило перед улюбленим.
Of course she wants to act all cute in front of the guy she likes.
Я теж!
I do it too!
Фу, фу.
Gross, gross.
У сенсі "фу"?!
What do you mean, "gross"?!
Ну бачиш?
See? There you go.
Хіба це мило?
How is that cute?
Це через твої слова.
This happens because you say pointless things-
Не зважай.
Well, never mind that.
Мімі говорила з тобою?
Has Mimi-chan contacted you?
Так.
Yeah.
Позвала погуляти утрьох.
She said the three of us should do something after school today.
Нащо?
W-Why?
Після викриття вона налаштована серйозно?
Now that her cover is blown, Mimi-chan's going to get serious, right?
Кажеш "серйозно"?
What do you mean by "serious"?
Чи встоїть Отані перед такою красунею?
What would happen to an idiot like Otani if a pretty girl like her got serious about him?
Я не програю!
I'm not going to lose!
Я не дам пропасти моїм зусиллям!
I'm not going to let all of my efforts go to waste!
Ачику, ходімо куди забажаєш.
We'll go wherever you want, A-chan.
Добре?
That's okay, right?
Добре.
It's fine.
Гей, ви двоє...
H-Hold on, you two...
Ходімо, Ачику.
Let's go, A-chan.
Будь ласка, просто йдіть вже.
Please, just go away, both of you.
Круто!
Sweet!
Що перше? Що перше?
What should we play? What should we play?
Там халява. Погнали!
That one's free. Let's go!
Круто!
Awesome!
Ачику?
A-chan?
Де Мімі?
Where's Mimi-chan?
Ось ти де.
There you are.
Мімі, приєднуйся.
Mimi-chan, come play with us.
Я додому.
I'm going home.
Що?
What?
Я додому!
I'm going home!
Мімі!
Mimi!
Я маю дещо сказати.
There's something I need to say to you properly.
Не треба.
I don't want to hear it.
Ти відмовиш мені?
You're going to reject me, right?
Мімі...
Mimi-chan...
Mimi...
Ні.
No.
Мімі.
Mimi.
Кажу ні!
I said no!
Мімі! Послухай!
Mimi! Listen to me!
Ні! Я не хочу!
No! I don't want to hear it!
Щодо Коїзумі...
About Koizumi, I...
Ні!!! Ні!!! Годі!!!
No!!! No!!! Stop!!!
Мімі!
Mimi!
Ні!!!
No!!!
Я...
I...
Мовчи!!
Don't say it!!!
Дурепо!
Idiot!
Що за...
Wh-What the...
Я думала Отані подобається тобі сильніше!
I thought you liked Otani more than me!
Про що ти кажеш?
Was that all just talk?
Ти його дівчина! Ніби ти розумієш мої почуття!
You're his girlfriend! Like you'd know how it feels to be rejected!
Я знаю! Він двічі мені відмовив!
I do know! I was rejected too! Twice!
Я теж думала здатись,
I thought about giving up too,
але я продовжувала старатись.
but in the end I kept trying.
Неможливо.
No way.
Хоч ми й зустрічаємось,
I might be his girlfriend now,
але він зве мене гидкою дурепою.
but he calls me an idiot, and says I'm gross all the time.
Я навіть точно не знаю чи подобаюсь йому.
I can hardly tell whether he actually likes me or not.
Що ти кажеш?
Hey, what're you sayi-
Але я невиразно кохаю його.
But I love him more than I can say, so it's fine.
Я не віддам Отані тому, хто одразу тікає.
I'm not going to give Otani up to someone who just runs away when they get rejected.
Тож Мімі втекла розлючена?
So, did Mimi-chan storm off?
Ні, ні.
No, no.
Сказала, що не зможе конкурувати з такою дурепою.
She said she can't deal with an idiot like you, so she's giving up on me.
Та що це таке?
What's up with that?
Думаю, їй було дуже боляче, коли ти уперше їй відмовив
It must have hurt her a lot the first time you rejected her.
Але вона з усих сил намагалась добитися тебе.
But she worked hard to win you over.
Ця дівчина неймовірна.
She really is amazing, that girl.
Що ти там казала?
What was that you were saying back there?
Про мої почуття до тебе.
Something about not being able to tell whether I actually like you or not, wasn't it?
А, та то просто...
Ahh, that was just...
Гарно придумав.
You deliberately stood on higher steps.
На землі це було б дивно
Well, it wouldn't have been as cool if we were standing on level ground.
Ходімо.
Let's go.
Стільки всього сталося,
A lot has happened...
але сподіваюсь отак буде надалі
but from now on, I hope we can be together like this...
й назавжди.
...forever.
Ви пишете тест?
Are you writing test questions?
А, ні.
Ah, no.
Переглядаю опитування учнів.
I was just looking over what the students aim to do in the future.
Вже час робити вибір на майбутнє.
It's almost time for them to make their final decisions, isn't it?
Це точно.
That it is.
Схоже наш дует коміків розпався.
It looks like All Hanshin-Kyojin will finally have a break up.
Career Guidance Questionnaire Name: Otani Atsushi Future Plans University тут треба зробити написи "Опитування з профорієнтації" Ім'я Отані Ацуші Запланований університет
Career Guidance Questionnaire Name: Otani Atsushi Future Plans University
Ти вступатимеш?
Are you going to go to a university?
Неможливо!
Impossible!
Гааа?
Huh?
Що робитимем як ти поїдеш, Отані?
What are we going to do while your away, Otani?
Зворушливий комплекс. Звор ком.
Lovely Complex~ Love Com.
Далі: Передчуття розлуки?! Різні шляхи Отані та Ріси.
Next: Premonition of Separation?! The Different Paths Risa and Otani Will Walk.
Передчуття розлуки?! Різні шляхи Отані та Ріси.
Premonition of Separation?! The Different Paths Risa and Otani Will Walk!
Не пропустіть!
Be sure to watch!